<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Hacking on The NullCereal Blog</title><link>https://nullcereal.com/tags/hacking/</link><description>Recent content in Hacking on The NullCereal Blog</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 06 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://nullcereal.com/tags/hacking/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>The Planets:Mercury Walkthrough</title><link>https://nullcereal.com/2021/12/the-planetsmercury-walkthrough/</link><pubDate>Mon, 06 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nullcereal.com/2021/12/the-planetsmercury-walkthrough/</guid><description>This is a quick walkthrough of the beginner-ish CTF machine &amp;ldquo;The Planets:Mercury&amp;rdquo; on Vulnhub.
****Spoiler Alert**** ****Spoiler Alert**** Nmap Scan: It looks like we have a Python WSGIserver under port 8080, but browsing the root directory was a dud, so let&amp;rsquo;s see if we can enumerate any more info from a Nikto scan:
Here we can see Nikto picked up directory browsing under the /SilverStream directory, so let&amp;rsquo;s take a look at that:</description></item><item><title>The Planets:Earth Walkthrough</title><link>https://nullcereal.com/2021/12/the-planetsearth-walkthrough/</link><pubDate>Fri, 03 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nullcereal.com/2021/12/the-planetsearth-walkthrough/</guid><description>This is a walkthrough of the beginner-ish CTF machine &amp;ldquo;The Planets:Earth&amp;rdquo; on Vulnhub.
****Spoiler Alert**** ****Spoiler Alert**** Shaking off a lot of cobwebs here, ok, obligatory nmap scan of Earth shows the following open ports: Some notable items here are the two DNS names identified in the certificate under port 443 as Subject Alternative Names (SANs) as earth.local and terratest.earth.local. These need to be added to the /etc/hosts file for sure for additional testing of server header goodies.</description></item><item><title>WestWild Walkthrough</title><link>https://nullcereal.com/2019/09/westwild-walkthrough/</link><pubDate>Fri, 06 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nullcereal.com/2019/09/westwild-walkthrough/</guid><description>This is a walkthrough of the beginner-level CTF machine &amp;ldquo;WestWild&amp;rdquo; on Vulnhub.
****Spoiler Alert**** ****Spoiler Alert**** So there is an obvious web page here after bootup, but it&amp;rsquo;s a red herring and we&amp;rsquo;ll rely on our trusty nmap scan:
Ok, let&amp;rsquo;s see if nikto turns up anything for HTTP:
Doesn&amp;rsquo;t look like anything special to me. Let&amp;rsquo;s take a look at Samba and see if enum4linux turns up anything interesting:</description></item><item><title>Matrix Walkthrough</title><link>https://nullcereal.com/2018/11/matrix-walkthrough/</link><pubDate>Fri, 16 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nullcereal.com/2018/11/matrix-walkthrough/</guid><description>This is a walkthrough of the Intermediate machine &amp;ldquo;Matrix&amp;rdquo; on Vulnhub. Let&amp;rsquo;s take the red pill and see where this story goes&amp;hellip;.
****Spoiler Alert**** ****Spoiler Alert**** So one of the scripts I run includes what I label as a &amp;ldquo;shotgun&amp;rdquo; option, and is essentially nmap -A. Running it here gives the following output:
This shows a typical OpenSSH server with non-typical Python SimpleHTTPServer modules running under ports 80 and 31337. Let&amp;rsquo;s look at these one at a time.</description></item><item><title>SolidState Walkthrough</title><link>https://nullcereal.com/2018/11/solidstate-walkthrough/</link><pubDate>Wed, 14 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nullcereal.com/2018/11/solidstate-walkthrough/</guid><description>This is a walkthrough of the CTF machine &amp;ldquo;SolidState&amp;rdquo; (originally on HackTheBox), now on Vulnhub. There are many writeups like it, and this one is mine.
****Spoiler Alert**** ****Spoiler Alert**** This was a great classic CTF, with some twists and multiple ways to gain a low privilege shell. Let&amp;rsquo;s grab our nmap scan and see what our options are:
Ok, so when I see any service that looks like something other than generic (like sendmail or postfix), or bigname (like MS), I tend to think that it&amp;rsquo;s a great place to look for public exploits.</description></item><item><title>Stapler Walkthrough</title><link>https://nullcereal.com/2018/11/stapler-walkthrough/</link><pubDate>Sat, 10 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nullcereal.com/2018/11/stapler-walkthrough/</guid><description>This is a walkthrough of the CTF machine &amp;ldquo;Stapler&amp;rdquo; on Vulnhub. This is a great machine for practicing enumeration :)
****Spoiler Alert**** ****Spoiler Alert**** Let&amp;rsquo;s jump all in with an extended TCP Nmap scan (nmap -A recommended, but too much info to list here):
Wow, ports a-plenty! For these CTF machines this result is always bittersweet since that&amp;rsquo;s just that much more possible dead ends. For brevity here, I&amp;rsquo;ll list some of the avenues I followed here:</description></item><item><title>Brainpan Walkthrough</title><link>https://nullcereal.com/2018/09/brainpan-walkthrough/</link><pubDate>Mon, 24 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nullcereal.com/2018/09/brainpan-walkthrough/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;ve had Brainpan downloaded for awhile and for some reason I haven&amp;rsquo;t ran it, so having a couple of hours last night I decided to see what it was all about. Unbeknownst to me, it was exactly what I was needing&amp;hellip;
****Spoiler Alert**** ****Spoiler Alert**** I had been wanting to practice buffer overflows for my upcoming OSCP test, and have been working on getting Windows machine setup just for this running vulnserver or something similar.</description></item><item><title>GeminiV2 Walkthrough</title><link>https://nullcereal.com/2018/09/geminiv2-walkthrough/</link><pubDate>Mon, 24 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nullcereal.com/2018/09/geminiv2-walkthrough/</guid><description>This is a walkthrough of the CTF machine &amp;ldquo;Gemini2&amp;rdquo; on Vulnhub. A tough VM, with lots of learning potential!
****Spoiler Alert**** ****Spoiler Alert**** I seem to always be doing these CTFs in reverse order. I&amp;rsquo;ll be going back to do GeminiV1 after this, but for me this was very challenging and fun. I learned from both a web application and privilege escalation perspective as this one seemed to be very real-world based.</description></item><item><title>Zico2 Walkthrough</title><link>https://nullcereal.com/2018/09/zico2-walkthrough/</link><pubDate>Mon, 03 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nullcereal.com/2018/09/zico2-walkthrough/</guid><description>Here we go. Walkthrough for Zico2 is happening in 3&amp;hellip;.2&amp;hellip;.1.
****Spoiler Alert**** ****Spoiler Alert**** For me this was a sleeper of a CTF. I had the box right up to a low privilege shell in a matter of minutes, but popping a shell and escalating from there took much longer than I anticipated. It was a very informative and fun VM. Let&amp;rsquo;s get to crack&amp;rsquo;n!
Initial Nmap shows HTTP, SSH, &amp;amp; RPC:</description></item><item><title>Bulldog Original Walkthrough</title><link>https://nullcereal.com/2018/08/bulldog-original-walkthrough/</link><pubDate>Fri, 31 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nullcereal.com/2018/08/bulldog-original-walkthrough/</guid><description>After completing Bulldog-2 I had to take a shot at the original Bulldog-1. How did it fare to the sequel? Let&amp;rsquo;s find out!
****Spoiler Alert**** ****Spoiler Alert**** Ennumeration of this box initially showed some interesting things to keep in mind:
The first as seen above is that well-known services (like SSH), will not always show up on their associated port, and can be assigned at the admin&amp;rsquo;s whimsy. Although that doesn&amp;rsquo;t mean it&amp;rsquo;s any less detectable.</description></item><item><title>Bulldog2 Walkthrough</title><link>https://nullcereal.com/2018/08/bulldog2-walkthrough/</link><pubDate>Wed, 29 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nullcereal.com/2018/08/bulldog2-walkthrough/</guid><description>This is a walkthrough of the CTF machine &amp;ldquo;Bulldog2&amp;rdquo; on Vulnhub. For me this was a challenging VM to beat! I like one&amp;rsquo;s like these because they challenge me while still being enjoyable.
****Spoiler Alert**** ****Spoiler Alert**** So after initial bootup we grab the IP and perform the obligatory nmap scan:
Looks like slim pickings with a single website. Let&amp;rsquo;s take a look at Bulldog.social:
Nice. Another social media site selling data to vendors.</description></item><item><title>Toppo Walkthrough</title><link>https://nullcereal.com/2018/08/toppo-walkthrough/</link><pubDate>Fri, 24 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nullcereal.com/2018/08/toppo-walkthrough/</guid><description>This is a walkthrough of the CTF machine &amp;ldquo;Toppo&amp;rdquo; on Vulnhub. It&amp;rsquo;s an easy machine so I thought that would make a good first post here :)
****Spoiler Alert**** ****Spoiler Alert**** So after an nmap -A we get the following output: A short visit to the site on port 80 reveals a no frills blog, so we run Nikto for some additional information: An admin directory with indexing enabled could be interesting.</description></item></channel></rss>