<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Blog on The NullCereal Blog</title><link>https://nullcereal.com/categories/blog/</link><description>Recent content in Blog on The NullCereal Blog</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 04 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://nullcereal.com/categories/blog/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Cookie Security, Wordle, and You</title><link>https://nullcereal.com/2022/02/cookie-security-wordle-and-you/</link><pubDate>Fri, 04 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nullcereal.com/2022/02/cookie-security-wordle-and-you/</guid><description>&lt;p>Websites run on the HypterText Transfer Protocol (HTTP). Sites that need to keep up with specific information about you (or how you interact with the site) save small files called &amp;ldquo;cookies&amp;rdquo; on your computer. Legitimate sites (ones that gather, and process information about you) are obligated to have a privacy policy posted somewhere on their website that will tell you what they collect, how they utilize cookies and other web &amp;ldquo;beacons&amp;rdquo; or trackers, and generally what they intend on doing with said data they&amp;rsquo;ve collected. Additionally, sites that store these cookies tell the browser how they are to be accessed and under what conditions, which can be under secure or insecure methods.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Sites that do not implement secure cookie handling can end up exposing sensitive data to attackers, so it&amp;rsquo;s important to know good the basics around cookie hygiene. Read on to see how sites can secure these values, how you can check the security of these values, remove them when needed, and an extra bit on how to win at the popular &lt;em>Wordle&lt;/em> word game the first time, every time!&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Going Phishing for CopyCats</title><link>https://nullcereal.com/2022/01/going-phishing-for-copycats/</link><pubDate>Thu, 13 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nullcereal.com/2022/01/going-phishing-for-copycats/</guid><description>&lt;p>If you&amp;rsquo;re in charge of a domain that others visit on a regular basis, and you want to ensure that users continue to trust that domain, then you want to keep phishers and attackers from creating fakes and copies of it.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>PDF Parsing - Malicious URLs</title><link>https://nullcereal.com/2020/11/pdf-parsing-malicious-urls/</link><pubDate>Sun, 01 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nullcereal.com/2020/11/pdf-parsing-malicious-urls/</guid><description>&lt;p>Extracting a list of URLs from a PDF can be difficult. One of the tools that makes it a lot easier is &lt;em>pdf-parser&lt;/em> by &lt;a href="https://blog.didierstevens.com/">Didier Stevens&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>For now we&amp;rsquo;ll focus on &lt;a href="https://blog.didierstevens.com/programs/pdf-tools/">pdf-parser&lt;/a> for extracting URLs in PDFs. This is a powerful tool with many uses, the full scope of which is beyond this brief tutorial.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Select That Data! - Regular Expressions</title><link>https://nullcereal.com/2020/10/select-that-data-regular-expressions/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nullcereal.com/2020/10/select-that-data-regular-expressions/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://jessehouwing.net/content/images/2018/08/regex.jpg" alt="regex">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I&amp;rsquo;ll start off this post by saying that I &lt;strong>DO NOT&lt;/strong> claim to be a &amp;ldquo;RegExpert&amp;rdquo; (Regular Expression Expert). I claim to be an expert in only a couple of things in life:&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>Knowing how to give good doggos belly rubs.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Not thinking of anything in particular.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;p>But because neither of these things pays the bills (yet), I&amp;rsquo;ve found that a little knowledge in regular expressions is a good thing to have. Better, sometimes having resources in your back pocket can be useful.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I&amp;rsquo;ll show a couple of small examples here, but will also give some examples of resources that can help with some of the tricky situations where regex is needed.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Security 404 - Disinformation Injection Attacks</title><link>https://nullcereal.com/2020/09/security-404-disinformation-injection-attacks/</link><pubDate>Thu, 10 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nullcereal.com/2020/09/security-404-disinformation-injection-attacks/</guid><description>&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Disinformation isn’t just a social engineering attack, it’s an buffer overflow attack of the mind.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>Most people may not be familiar with an information security vulnerability called a buffer overflow. Here&amp;rsquo;s a small example:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://www.hackingtutorials.org/wp-content/uploads/2016/12/buffer-overflow-strcpy-example.jpg" alt="bof">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Buffer Overflow attacks work when a program needs to accept input from the user (think of a program that asks for your username, like the example above). The issue is that the programmer uses a function like &lt;em>strcpy()&lt;/em> where the size of the destination is not specified. The problem here is two fold:
1. If you throw enough data into this input area, it can crash, resulting in a Denial of Service condition.
2. If you craft a specialized request, taking into account memory allocations, you can trick the program into running almost any code you want it to run.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Security 404 - Balancing Compromise</title><link>https://nullcereal.com/2020/07/security-404-balancing-compromise/</link><pubDate>Thu, 02 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nullcereal.com/2020/07/security-404-balancing-compromise/</guid><description>&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>The test of a first-rate intelligence is the ability to hold two opposed ideas in the mind at the same time and still retain the ability to function.
- F. Scott Fitzgerald&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>While I can&amp;rsquo;t speak to &lt;em>first-rate intelligence&lt;/em> I feel like this quote perfectly describes my role in information security. I do not hold a high-level position, but still, when it comes to influence in business, information security is a topic where even a lowly analyst is given unparalleled access and opportunity.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Because technology is centric to most business functions, any threat to that technology direct impacts the bottom line. This threat cycle is all well known by now. At this point most organizations have methods to determine risk, and threat model certain business decisions. This is part of my job and the basis for this post.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>